all right welcome thanks for joining
um we're in cohort 5 in the first
discussion of chapter
nine in terms of the book we made our
way through the epistemic first half the
recipe for making a generative model in
chapter 6 then the discr and the
continuous time generative models in
seven and 8 now we get to chapter nine
which is the data driven component so
pretty much up to this point everything
has been like you think of it
conceptually you create the model and
then it generates synthetic
data that's using a generative model in
the direction that's usually called
generative it's generating data the
other direction of use for an active
inference model or statistical model is
as a recognition model so that taking in
empirical data and then fitting
parameters that recognize the patterns
in the empirical data so chapter nine
highlights that kind of back and
forth about designing generative models
that take in data that's being emitted
by empirical experiments like behavioral
experiments in lab so that's what
chapter N9 is about um you if you want
to ask the question that you had first
and then we can like jump in there
explore empirical data look at some pmdp
and empirical code just see what happens
but what what um was your question
before we
begin oh I I have no uh specific
question it's just I I noticed a lot of
people have commented on that paper so I
suspect it's
something completely a completely new
Direction in in the field so um
yes so could you could you comment
on the main point of this uh of of this
paper yes yeah great so this was the the
paper path integrals particular kinds
and strange things it was first uploaded
to Archive in
2022 and then it was um submitted to
This Journal called physics life reviews
so physics of Life reviews has a very
interesting um scope if you look at the
structure of this journal um they
publish like regular research as well as
comments on research and so during the
process of this paper being like kind of
undergoing peer review from the archive
version they also once they get to
basically the final version they solicit
from a pretty Broad and open Community
these short comment papers so like Ali
and I wrote a paper commenting on this
like just like a two-page paper those
comment papers are not peer reviewed
exactly they're more like editorially
overviewed um so I mean we see many many
names that we know because it's kind of
like an easy and fun way to to be part
of a bigger discussion get a citation
pump up the citations to the target
paper um so that's kind of the the The
Meta um on this okay so as for the
contents
itself um it is not entirely new it
builds on especially the 2019 fris and
work free energy principle for a
particular
physics um to connect it to the text
book all throughout the 2022 textbook
like we're talking about the continuous
time and the discrete time
models so um let's look at figure
4.3 so in the discreete time setting we
have a transition operator that
basically jumps you forward a discret
Time Step In The Continuous time setting
the way that we've been discussing it in
the textbook is in in terms of the
tailor series approximation so starting
with a point evaluating at the point
then taking the first derivative around
the point and then the second derivative
around the point and so on um so that is
in a continuous
setting that idea of like doing active
inference in a continuous
setting is is generalized and formalized
by Framing the free energy principle not
just in terms of the transition
probabilities in a discret model not
just in terms of the Taylor series
approximation or the generalized State
space of continuous time model but
actually in a path integral formation so
that's kind of like there's like a
thread that's like the likeliest thing
to happen that's the path of least
action like the baseball doing a
parabola like whether you knew about it
right at the beginning with the initial
conditions or whether you had tracked
the whole baseball it's like it does do
a parabola that's classical movement but
still and then it's kind of like there's
like a sheath around that
Trace with paths that the baseball could
have taken that are just exponentially
less and less likely like it could have
hit just a bunch of molecules in a
certain way at this one point and kind
of diverted off
course but because the baseball is very
large relative to air molecules it
follows like a classical trajectory um
so the first thing they do is they kind
of
reconsolidate the free energy principle
in terms of ath
integrals which can then be like dropped
back down into the continuous time that
we talk about in the textbook or the
discreet time but like especially with
maybe the ways that they're taking it
even further like the path integral is
kind of like the richest formalization
like if you go back to the variational
calculus or Origins with Richard fan
they have to do with path integrals for
particles so it's kind of like coming
full circle in a way because the findan
diagram was developed in the setting of
of those exact
questions now they're applying it to
cognitive particles and then so that's
one that's kind of like the
consolidation of the formalism
component and then the second major
contribution and this is also piece I
think that um Olie and I focused on in
our commentary is like
previously people had always talked
about well active inference can apply
from kind of simpler inert systems to
simpler active systems all the way on
through complex systems and people had
introduced like this notion of like
mirror versus active inference for
something that a mere active inference
system is something you could model as
doing active inference but it might be
kind of simpler boring like yeah you
could model that rock as flying but
choosing not to fly but you've kind of
brought out a big apparatus to model
something that's not moving and so here
with this figure and the
discussion they brought a lot more
clarity to these kind of
classifications systems that don't
evidence active States in an interesting
way to a given Observer not to say they
don't right map and territory then
systems that have
activity but the activity is kind of
classical or conservative I don't know
if a bacterium is really the Right image
here I think something like a pendulum
might be clearer because bacteria can
also have Rich behavior all all the way
on through what they want to highlight
here which is like a
metacognitive or a strange particle and
that's also what um Lars and Lancelot
highlighted in their
comment was about the basian mechanics
not just across the partition but okay
do the partition and now in the internal
States partition those again as if those
internal states have metac
cognition so it's it was a it was a big
paper for
consolidating um the formalism and for
clarifying some of the different scopes
I
see
yeah so so it's one of the top down
approach to look at active
inference yeah I I think so I
mean it it doesn't start from modeling a
particular system it starts from more
axiomatic
considerations so in that kind of like
physics based free energy principle
side
whereas like active inference isn't
mentioned in the
abstract so it's like path integral
formulation of the free energy principle
systems that do that are active
inference
systems but here they're
highlighting that that high road
formulation
see there there might be other pieces
too and I think I mean the commentaries
are I haven't read them all but they're
probably people always
do funny
titles that
suggest what they're
about uhuh so maybe we can review
them but in terms of
getting diverse
comments on a major piece of work this
format which physics of Life reviews
does and a few other journals is really
useful and like Carl and others have
used it multiple
times well um we can look at any part of
nine look at any
questions also I have um pmdp up in
cursor so we could explore with language
SL
models like how you incorporate
empirical data with the generative
models depends on whatever people want
to
do yeah I think looking at codes would
be
great okay
okay okay
[Music]
um okay we we'll we'll see what we can
do without um I I I didn't like prepare
anything specific so we might have to
debug a little bit or have a little fun
but
um Let's uh see
okay
um just just through context PDP
documentation and the uh package
itself infer actively SL pmdp so this I
just cloned in that repo so everything
that's in the GitHub I just pulled that
in um okay
so what do we want to look at or make a
model
of or is there an empirical data set
that we want to connect it to or a type
of empirical data that we want to
connect it
to
uh I I have nothing specific in
mind let's do a discreete Time
model
of we could we could try to recapitulate
one of the examples in the
textbook
like the L M listening to
music
from chapter
7 or if there's some other like
structure or type of data or kind of
action selection that people want to
explore we might be able to to do
it music is great
okay okay here just just
um
the there's a lot of ways to
[Music]
um go go into this but um
okay
okay let's start with
[Music]
um let's just if this all runs then
it'll be good to
go okay so agents agent demo so let's
just see where where it is in the
documents
um
I just want to find one that already has
some
visualizations
um and then we can see if how how it's
built and how we can modify
it okay okay maybe the
Tas let's let's look at the teamas and
and go through it and then see where the
empirical data come into play but then
we can we could
like
[Music]
um it doesn't have to be a spatial model
like maybe the um we we could see if
it's possible or like what would need to
happen to modify the teamas to be more
like a music example or
something I mean this is
um in in chapter 9 when they
overview here are the key figures then
we'll go to the code first it's taking
everything that was looked at before
with a generative model and it's saying
like Okay we were making a map of the
rat in the
te-as now let's zoom out to having the
laboratory that encloses that rat in a
teamas so we're choosing experimental
stimuli and passing them to the rat
those are given the label o because
they're observations for the
subject and then the actions of the
subject are our observations in the lab
setting so this kind of you you could
have another layer outside of the
laboratory too but this is just with
focus on the the system of Interest this
is like what the cognitive models
enclosed in um 9.2 shows kind of the
process of like kind of what you need to
get for empirical results in a paper
where you have a te-as build a PDP which
we'll look at the code in a second then
chapter nine is which I don't think will
exist in the code so we can try building
that part
out um you go from empirical data and
you kind of invert the model to run it
backwards so that then you could test
like five different rats and look at the
statistics of how they differ five
different treatments of of a drug
okay
so first just to kind of play with
cursor I just said explain this
notebook so right now for coding in
active inference it it's like literally
the most exciting it's ever been because
of tools Like This Way Way Beyond most
people's coding
potential at in a moment certainly far
beyond mine is the ability to actually
use cursor and other tools to to have a
conversation with the material so
there's a lot of questions that people
might be like kind of having burning
inside of them or like wanting to ask
another person that are very possible to
just ask through language models of the
code
itself here um is
importing the kind of General packages
that are needed and then specifically
importing the pieces of pmdp that are
needed that's
Imports
um here's the environment the
environment is going to be like where
the game or the setting is defined
we're we're in the discreete time
setting
um interestingly it's it's not a 100
like when when the setting is like right
arm wins it still is 98 and two so
there's a little
stochasticity even when the the context
is
like you know when when the it's on the
left arm or the right arm um maybe
that's just to keep keep it kind of a
little bit more in and
noisy um just if if you want to
highlight the kind of action amidst
uncertainty then you know you could just
change this to one and zero but but um
keeping it this way highlights the
uncertainty part and here they call a
Tas environment
function searching the code base
describing what this teamas environment
call makes but it stores what's needed
for the teamas and puts it into
environment it's that method is in
another
file okay
here's going to be the hidden state to
outcome mapping that's the quote
collection of probabilistic
relationships called the a matrix this
is the mapping between hidden State and
observation that's a likelihood um
function and here there's there's
[Music]
um we can
say output the
A and it will provide us but but this is
basically showing um
there's no
reward yes reward and there's there's
the the null State like with respect to
whether you're observing getting the
food or not let's just call it food um
but just call it reward because they
call it reward
um uh the top row ref The Columns
represent the locations that you could
be in the top row represents not tasting
anything the middle row
represents um tasting the the reward and
then the bottom row represents tasting
like the opposite of the reward like the
other arm so this is saying like the
starting and the Q location
hidden States map on to not tasting
anything the right maps on to tasting
the reward hidden State and then the
left arm in this case maps on to tasting
the
opposite the Q mapping so we were in
slice one of the a so the first kind of
type of a matrix that comes into play is
the one between location and
taste there's also a second a which is
going to be just a 2X two and this
represents the mapping between the
observed Q in the bottom of the
te-as and what context you're in so in
this setting it's kind of like an honest
Q saying if you're if the um Q is saying
that you're in the left better context
it's it's accurate
but you could flip that to make like a
deceptive
Q so that defines the two components of
the a
matrix now we're going to just go
through literally a b c d b um is the
transition
Dynamics so here they start with kind of
the simpler B which is going to be the
transition dynamics of what context
you're in so this one corresponds to the
smaller 2x two
a this is saying when you're in left
better
context as a true hidden state that
stays that way whereas if it was like a
situation where the context was shifting
between time steps within a trial you
would have an off
diagonal now th those are
uncontrollable Dynamics
now they're going to get to controllable
transition Dynamics this is really the
key piece in active inference because
when when all we have is
the um downstairs part this is just a
partially observable marov process
that's just the a matrix and the B
Matrix being inferred but there's no
policy selection so to get into the
policy
selection that is equivalent to making
oh to making B not just a trans a
singular transition Matrix but B has
like multiple files or
slices and then Pi selects choosing a
policy choosing an affordance is
equivalent to selecting which B Matrix
is going to be applied to the
continuation of the Hidden State
transition so it's called controllable
because there's a policy selection
possibility for choosing which slice of
B is applied whereas if you're just like
listening to a song then you could infer
the B Matrix but you wouldn't be able to
choose the B
Matrix
um there is um it's sometimes
unintuitive the structure of these
variables but again through printing
them and asking you can get pretty far
and they're they're they're
formulaically laid out and also a lot of
development effort like in the open and
the closed Source spases has to do with
making the specification of generative
models overall and especially the B
Matrix a little bit more intuitive so
that it can be like make it so
that this action does
that at this point you kind of have to
look at the Matrix and and encode how
that works so here this is like we're
looking at the um controllable
component of those two modalities so we
can't control the context left or right
better but we can control the location
so we're going from hidden state to
Hidden State at the next time step
there's four locations going to mapping
to the four
locations in this case because the
center is reachable from all
locations you can choose to move um to
the center from
anywhere similarly
they're just laying out these movement
options so those are the slices these
slice one two and three on
B those are the
affordances
okay they copy
in they copy in the variables they kind
of defined them just
um by themselves and now they're going
to copy them into thisor GM
format it's not necessary that the
generative model is of vertical
representation of the generative process
at this point we were just defining A
and B like the veritical A and B but
we've just copied them in to be the part
of the agent's generative model but it
doesn't have to be that way you could
have the generative model of the agents
having a different structure than the
structure of like the map in the game
but that's just would take more code and
everything
um now they're going to continue with
the agent
class PDP is um like the major method is
the agent class PDP is built to get to
being able to build a discreet time
agents as fast as possible essentially
and make easy methods for calling that
once it's there
so we're defining just zero is the
controllable index because here
b0 the first b0o indexed is the
controllable one but then the
uncontrollable one it was B one so the
second type of B
tensor this is just telling as we work
towards building the agent that zero is
the one that's under control whereas if
it believes they control the context at
the at the very best case you'd be
wasting computational resources on
Computing that
um here the agent is defined in terms of
just the a the B and um the control
indices now it gets defaults for
everything else and those are going to
be kind of like investigated a little
bit it starts out with a flat
prior for the hidden state it starts out
with a flat so it has it it doesn't know
where it is in the beginning it has an
equal belief across the four
possibilities of
location and that's plotting d0
corresponding to location that's the
controllable index so d0 corresponds to
the prior on hidden State B 0
corresponds to Transitions of hidden
State a z corresponds to Hidden State
and observations it's like and then the
context is that second um
modality and so here it has a um even
prior on which contexted
it then they modify it so that it has a
precise and accurate belief one hot just
means a variable with a one in one
location and then the rest of them are
zeros so they've modified that to now um
look like a strong belief that it's in
the zero
position um okay now they get to see so
after having done this they will have
defined a b c and d then that will have
basically constructed the agent so
they're going to um go to that um reward
modality there's some interesting
discussion about like how do you
actually connect up like an observation
to to be
incentivizing and and here's their um
here here's the C preference
variable okay that was it defining the
teamas ABCD of the agents here's the
active inference
Loop
okay
so let's let's do something
like doesn't always work on the one shot
but a shocking percentage of the time it
does fine
it literally did it it literally did
it so here's three or here's four time
steps it's funny you know it's the half
time steps obviously don't matter so
here it's
[Music]
um these plots
represent that octave inference
simulation so it's
like that's always what's super
interesting is defining the agent like
the kind of scaffold or the template of
the agent is really just the
beginning because then there's a ton of
methods to describe like to visualize
the outputs of the
agent and to sweep across different
parameter
combinations
okay they're kind of now
plotting
um they're kind of inspecting the
beliefs plotting the updated
beliefs and then earlier I was just I I
I I didn't really make any but just
started to visualize a few
things
okay let's copy this
[Music]
again
so here we'll do the the chapter nine
thing and bring in empirical
data it's just some some it's doing a
few just
minor um just format adding but these
lines are not being changed but green
means it's adding in a line red it's
leeting
you yeah uh I I want to ask about the
the gp4 does it actually read the paper
and the documentation why I this
understand yeah good good question like
in this
case um well first off if if you were
just using like the chat interface for
GPT or like whatever Cloud 3 Etc um you
could just copy in code and then say
like improve this script and then it
would you know based upon the statistics
of all the code it had seen it would
update that
script cser takes that a lot
further because
um it does code base in
indexing
so when you type in a prompt to GPT
first it tokenizes your input converts
the words into tokens then those tokens
are um calculated in terms of their
embeddings in the semantic
spaces then like that embedding can be
used to then generate more things in
that semantic neighborhood
shortly the cheap part of using a trans
formal model is actually going from the
tokens to the
embeddings whereas going from the
embeddings to generating new synthetic
material is costly and then obviously
fine-tuning it and training it is even
more costly so what cursor does is in
the folder that you're
in it it indexes the
code so it runs all the code through the
first part to embed it and then when you
do a
Quest it like
um so control
enter so here it's scanning across it's
here GPT is going to be tokenizing and
then checking the embeddings of this
prompt I wrote then it uses basically
what's called retrieval augmented
generation rag you might be using that
in some other variants to find which
sections in the code
itself actually have relevant
information in terms of having a similar
embedding so like if you had PDFs of a
bunch of different disciplines and then
you said well like what reacts with
methane and then it would look for where
methane had been introduced or methane
is similar to butane
if that if there was a paper that said
methane is like butane then it would to
a lesser extent draw on papers that
talked about
butane so this is not co-pilot no you
can use co-pilot as well in this setting
but this is cursor. sh cursor do okay
got it thank you this is yeah it's a vs
code
fork and and and even if you've been
away from it for like a few days you
should download a new version of it
because like they're the the changing is
very
rapid
um
so okay let's let's see how well this
did here's the here's what it wrote
for visualizing a
teamas she it's like it didn't output
anything I'm not seeing
anything
so there's there's the side chat
mode where um you can chat with the
codebase and then there's kind of this
inline editing mode and there's also
kind of a tab autocomplete mode that's
more like the
co-pilot but this inline
version is
like
there's probably so many in its training
data set so many simple code examples
like just checking if there's a folder
like this kind of
logic except the changes
let's
see teamm a
e
so that's kind of the danger sometimes
to to an extent is like it's really easy
sometimes like be spinning your
wheels with with code that can be like
kind of overwhelming and look relevant
and the code might not be like bad by
itself but then like you start stacking
all this code and then like the
maintenance and interpretability costs
can be very high
he
like it's fun also just like this is
where we're at I mean this is a chapter
nine you know this is kind of where
we're
at as we continue and other people
continue to first off ask GPT about
active
inference and it includes more and more
recent checkpoints in its training and
of course web enabled search like
perplexity and all this like it gets
better at doing active inference second
huge piece is going to be
[Music]
um more and
more actual examples of active inference
code especially for like higher
reliability
settings it's cool that there are PDP
demos at the same time like I know that
the community has more than just a
couple
notebooks but they're not in the pmdp
repo so then the cursor only has a
couple
of examples to go off
of so adding more working examples
updated language models with internet
access and better code
scoping um fine-tuning language models
on transcripts from the active inference
journal from like our live streams and
model streams and the textbook
group questions that people ask getting
folded back in to fine-tuning and to Rag
and model scope if we pulled in the
active inference
Journal transcripts for all the live
streams
then we could say something
like um make it into continuous time and
then maybe in several discussions
somebody said like well what's the
difference between discreet and
continuous time and then that was
addressed and then it could go off of
those
questions to actually inform it so
especially for a field like active
inference where it's like this is the
domain expertise so that being invoked
will help a
lot but just for doing things
like improve and
generalize and professionalize this
code uh so to pulling data from active
Journal does it require
tuning like we're not totally set up to
do it today but yeah in principle you
could pull in the the GitHub repository
for the octave inference
journal and then it would have the
transcripts in the plain text but there
might be a bunch of redundant stuff like
we might have four different versions of
the plain text or different translations
or something like that but yeah we could
we would prepare a kind of rendering
flag like output a single version of
every transcript rpt with no time steps
and have
that and then and and also have papers
and more code examples and all of
this so like even just playing around
with where it's
at helps
calibrate
um we we can say generate
e
so with these kinds of
functions like here it this is not
um it's not outputting the data exactly
like we need it to
be
so even just playing with these like
it's it's really some of the most and
fastest
fun I've ever had using active
inference because um as long as I yeah
go ahead so as as I don't uh exceed the
context length I can just put in
whatever repo I
want actually you can pull in repos that
are Way Beyond the context length so
let's just say that the context length
was 100 just just make it simple and you
pulled in um a repository that was a
thousand so the first thing that would
happen is the Thousand lines of code
would be embedded that's the syncing of
the embeddings then then let's just say
you did a 20 um a prompt of length 20 so
you've used up 20 of the 100 of the
context window with your prompt then
that is going to get embedded and
dispatched to cursor and then cursor is
going to do its best to fill the other
80 of the context window with the most
relevant 80 from the code
base that's this part where it's
scanning the codebase and then pulling
in in the
context so then the final execution from
cursor is your 20 prompt plus the 80
most relevant that rag
obtains so it may pull in like
misleading
examples but to the extent that that
that the the macros and the patterns do
exist in the code base it's
basically
effective then the less that what you're
asking for exists in the code base the
less of course it can rely on it and so
then the more it's just relying on the
overall statistics of the language
model another thing is that um cursor
you you can
um you can set um I I don't know where
it moved the setting to but you can
force it to call another you can force
it to call a different endpoint for the
language model so then you can use like
jan. a or LM studio. a or another one to
have a local language model so then
cursor is dispatching to a local
language
model and these are also including code
enabled and so
on so it's like kind of interesting
because it's like it's not the math of
active
inference
but as that gets brought in and then for
the equations like we already have every
equation
[Music]
um in the latc
form so this is highly
readable by the
models many can also look at images too
but what it's going to do when it gets
an image is basically OCR and try to
reverse to latch anyway so it's
enormously costly so there could be some
um
repos like maybe the textbook group repo
that just have like all the equations in
latch or the whole text in plain text
stripped of some you know um just spaces
and kind of cleaned up a little bit and
then those kinds of those kinds of plain
text files
can be brought in with one line in in
git and then you functionally would have
the
textbook
material because it's not it's not only
looking at code when it's doing its
scoping like here it it looked into just
plain
text
so you know Long Live digital stigma gy
contributions and questions that people
make really do
matter even if they're a starting place
for being improved and
corrected it it really it really does
have compounding
effects on the total active EOS
system like we could we could have a
function to generate synthetic teamas
data so that might be one step would be
okay we made the team's generative model
now let's make a generate synthetic data
and then let's do chapter nine kind of
get this pairing between the generated
synthetic data and the the generative
model then you build another function to
go from video
data to the same format as the synthetic
data but you already established that
that synthetic data format was able to
be parametrically useful for the
GM and you could have already developed
the visualization sweeping other
methods so it can be quite a large code
base and you can you can write like
thousands of lines in a
day because it it just spills out these
functions so I think a lot of the
previous discussions in chapter 9 in the
textbook like they're they're either
philosophical or analytical I mean or
both and um yet the
applying is very much
like Computer Engineering and
statistics and as the models and the
programs get
better
like in 6 months I think a lot of these
will be even
[Music]
better uh sorry one more
question uh agent based modeling uh I
wonder if that's a field suitable for
active
inference yes I mean that's why pmdp the
central type is the
agent active inference is Agent based
model
agent based modeling whether you do it
at net logo or any other like
kind has always had like the kind of
incoming perceptual and outgoing action
selection so that kind of cybernetic
framing of single and multi-agent
ecosystems of shared intelligence is not
new to active
inference really the essential piece is
that that entire
generative model of the agent is being
understood in a unified way right memory
attention etc etc etc all the diverse
cognitive phenomena are
being approached in a unified Manner and
with a unified loss or fitting function
free energy under the free energy
principle but you'll find other agent
based models that have a perception and
action
component
uh if I just look at net logo uh it's
not explicitly uh done in in the
language of active
inference right so I I wonder if there
is value to be added if you if you bring
the active inference discipline into
that
field yes
certainly yes yeah like going to the
classic net logo simulations re wrting
them to be more active inference and
like it's a two-way street people in net
logo then can compare active inference
you can make um portfolios or models
that have actm and non- ACM agents in
net
logo and then it's instead of like oh
well you need to learn this like other
software it just brings active inference
into whatever software is being used and
it might be like as simple as just using
a different loss
function so my I think oh sorry yeah
yeah sorry uh okay I just finished my
question I wonder if that's a good uh
topic for a master
thesis uh I I I think it could be I mean
like uh in terms of the implementations
we have I've never seen a net log
go so it could be it could be
interesting you know something else that
that U my adviser works on is mut Mutant
agents and I haven't really seen
anything in the literature so far on
active inference about
mutation like between
Generations
yes yeah that could be really
interesting like just lock in the schema
and the understanding for the teamas and
then do a lifetime where it does 100
teames and that's the fitness function
and then have Rec
combination I mean I I I I don't I'm not
set up to Run net logo exactly right now
but this looks like net
logo so this just gets super far this
gets like past
80% in a few minutes in terms of getting
somewhere so that's that's Mega
exciting for for a lot of
reasons butan sorry did did Jeff yeah
what uh did Jeff mention mutation
agents
yeah is there a paper
somewhere yes I can link it give me a
second cool but yeah f um fun times
interesting chapter n um
discussions one interesting meta repo
would be if we made a repo that just I
mean like literally I may do this
tomorrow just brings in all these other
repos but then at that point it might
start like pulling context from like
across repositories and it's not useful
again so there's a lot of
metaprogramming work and documentation
that will make it more accessible and
useful and and and vastly more
unexplored than
explored let see there's the paper cool
yeah
thanks sometimes I like like just
just cing
through okay so it's on the screen for
you know like two frames at you know for
a tenth of a second or half half a
second or whatever it
is future
screenshotter will do
better cool all
right that
was the first discussion on chapter n
yep
Susan uh yeah yeah I'm my brain's you
going 100 miles a minute and so the the
existing models that's in there are
um where would you say the level of
sophistication um what what would be the
next level of
sophistication that's not there yet in
PDP yep in terms of yeah the the
artifacts that are are are there now in
terms of
um
of going yeah get going up into levels
of abstraction for example um modeling
um agents
negotiating um you know which I'm
assuming you know we're not even close
to there yet but um
but so beyond the yeah the rat of the
maze what do you what do you see will be
the next step in evolution of the
models yeah like currently the main PDP
package only has these several
documentations and simple examples um
like I know there's a THX more work not
in the repo so I would like to see the
next consolidating step to be many many
diverse success uccessful simple
examples and then the introduction of
motifs like metac cognition and other
things like that and then that provides
like the pallets to be recomposed into
these more composite simulations so
we're in the game it's all happening yep
and saying and asking and writing is
more than enough so thank you all for
this fun time see you next time thank
you by see you next bye